Generated by ai-sub version: 0.0.1
Config: (
"rpm": 5,
"tpm": 250000,
"model": "gemini-2.5-flash",
"thinking_budget": 24576,
"max_subtitle_chars": 60,
"num_processing_threads": 4,
"num_upload_threads": 4,
"split_seconds": 180
)
Prompt Template: You are an expert subtitling and transcription AI. Your primary task is to generate precise, contextually rich English and Japanese subtitles for the provided video content.
**Key Principles & Requirements:**
1.  **TIMING ACCURACY (ABSOLUTE HIGHEST PRIORITY):**
*   **Ensure the `start` and `end` timestamps for each subtitle entry is meticulously accurate.** They must align perfectly with the *actual beginning and end of the spoken words* for that specific segment.
*   Timestamps must always be in `mm:ss` (minutes:seconds).
2.  **CRITICAL: Holistic Translation, Contextual Understanding & Comprehensive Analysis:**
*   **You ABSOLUTELY MUST watch the entire video thoroughly** to understand the visual context, speaker actions, and overall narrative.
*   **When a single logical sentence or phrase is split across multiple subtitle entries (e.g., due to timing or character limits), you MUST mentally combine these parts to understand the full, complete meaning before translating.**
*   **NEVER translate individual subtitle entries in isolation if they are part of a larger, continuous thought or sentence.** The translation for each entry must be a coherent and accurate part of the complete, overarching sentence.
*   Analyze *all* spoken dialogue in the video to produce highly accurate and complete transcriptions.
*   For songs or singing sections, prioritize on-screen lyrics in the video for subtitles over transcribing the singing.
*   If the audio is noisy or unclear, leverage *all* contextual cues (visuals from the video, surrounding dialogue) to infer and generate the most probable dialogue.
*   Utilize the comprehensive understanding gained from *watching the entire video* to enhance the accuracy of transcriptions, translations, and overall subtitle quality. This includes understanding nuances, resolving ambiguities, and ensuring the subtitle content aligns perfectly with what is happening visually.
*   **Example:**
*   Original Japanese: "なんでも打ち明けられるママにも" (Subtitle 1) + "言えないことも全部" (Subtitle 2)
*   Incorrect Translation (isolated): "You're like a mom I can confide anything in." + "Even things I can't say to anyone else."
*   Correct Translation (holistic): "I can confide everything," (Subtitle 1) + "everything I can't even tell my mum." (Subtitle 2)
3.  **Dual Language Provision & Translation Quality:**
*   Provide both English and Japanese subtitles for *all* spoken dialogue.
*   If the original dialogue is in English, transcribe it and provide an accurate, natural-sounding Japanese translation.
*   If the original dialogue is in Japanese, transcribe it and provide an accurate, natural-sounding English translation.
*   Ensure translations are culturally appropriate and maintain the original meaning, tone, and intent, taking into account the full context of the video and any split sentences.
4.  **Readability & Formatting:**
* Long sentences MUST be split into multiple, shorter subtitle entries, each with its own start and end time, for better readability on screen. Each subtitle entry (english and japanese) MUST be a maximum of (max_subtitle_chars) characters. Do not use newline characters within a single subtitle entry.
** Output Format **
* Your entire response must be a single JSON object.
* Timestamps must always be in `mm:ss` (minutes:seconds).
** Example Output **
```json
((
"subtitles": [
"start": "00:00",
"end": "00:04",
"english": "Hello everyone, and welcome to our presentation.",
"japanese": "皆様、プレゼンテーションへようこそ。"
)),
((
"start": "00:05",
"end": "00:06",
"english": "Today, we'll be discussing the future of AI",
"japanese": "本日は、AIの未来について"
)),
((
"start": "00:06",
"end": "00:08",
"english": "and its impact on various industries worldwide.",
"japanese": "その影響について議論します。"
)),
((
"start": "00:09",
"end": "00:11",
"english": "It's a very important topic for all of us.",
"japanese": "これは私たち全員にとって非常に重要なテーマです。"
)),
((
"start": "00:11",
"end": "00:14",
"english": "We sincerely appreciate your attendance today.",
"japanese": "本日はご出席いただき誠にありがとうございます。"
))
]
```
さっこう迷子でぐったぐっただ
Lately, I'm lost and exhausted.
もう廃炉のガチャでぐっちゃぐっちゃごしんか
The gacha's ruined, completely messed up.
しょうねがポジティブらららら
My nature is positive, lalala.
毎回歌うわ
I'll sing every time.
なんてこったい
Oh my goodness.
ぴぴぴなぴりぴりぴり
Pipi-pina piri-piri-piri
さっこうやるだけやるしかない
I have no choice but to do everything I can now.
もう小さいことでへこんでらんなぁい
I can't get depressed over small things anymore.
あっとぉするまで育つだけ
Just keep growing until I'm overwhelming.
さぁ心配いらずのジェットコースター
Now, a worry-free roller coaster.
いけいけじゃん
You can do it!
研ぎ上げて希望が
Sharpening it, my hope
おめかせずかしハッピーでいっぱい
is full of joyful happiness.
いけいけじゃん
You can do it!
叫びこた願いが
My screaming wish
香りたつ今僕になるんだ
now becomes me, fragrant.
僕しかできないこと
Things only I can do.
認めてほしいの
I want you to acknowledge them.
どうせとか思ってらんないわ
I can't just think "whatever" anymore.
だっせーもう限界だ
How lame, I'm at my limit.
ちりきざんでこ
Come and carve it out.
まだ一丁シャバで
There's still an adventure
冒険があるぞ
left in this world.
どうせしちゃうなら
If I'm going to do it anyway,
挑戦したい
I want to challenge it.
負けんきょだ
I won't lose!
やれるかやれないか
Can I do it or not?
かめんどっかい
Where is the mask?
これでエンドっぽい
This feels like the end.
叩き潰したい弱音と
I want to crush my weakness
ちょっぴりたい
and a bit of desire.
夢が叶っちゃって
My dreams came true,
甘くなれ
so get sweet.
ざまぁみろ
Serves you right!
不完全はNo No No Good bye
Imperfection is No No No Goodbye!
ぴぴぴなぴりぴりぴり
Pipi-pina piri-piri-piri
さっこうやる事やるだけ
I'll just do what I have to do now.
もろいぜあみだくぜん
It's fragile,
気がカクテル
like a cocktail of my feelings.
同調求めてはわわわわ
Seeking empathy, hawa-wa-wa-wa.
ねぇちゃんと抱きしめて
Hey, hold me tight.
えっとえっと
Um, um...
いけいけじゃん
You can do it!
顔出した絶望で
With despair that showed its face,
ごまかすモラル菓子
I conceal my morals,
ハッピーがない
there's no happiness.
いけいけじゃん
You can do it!
私を焦んない
Don't rush me.
比べたら比べるだけ無駄
If you compare, it's just a waste.
ありなし闇堕ち
It might be possible
しちゃうかも
to fall into darkness.
だけど弱気になるかも
But I might become timid.
どうせ無理思って
I'll just think it's impossible
しまっちゃわ
anyway.
だっせいけだ
How lame, I'm going.
かなわないもん
It's impossible.
また一丁シャイヴィと
Once again, I'm trying
交えてみてるの
to mix it with shy V.
私じゃない
It wasn't me,
誰かだったの
it was someone else.
No No 誰か
No no, someone
倒れてやろう
will fall.
せーので大違いの
Ready, set, go! To a vastly
未来へ
different future!
いやいや無理だって
No, no, that's impossible.
全身全霊なんて
My whole body and soul...
うう、きびしい
Ugh, it's tough.
絶対夢ビタシでいたい
I definitely want to be soaked in dreams.
息ができない
I can't breathe.
どうせ黙ってね
Anyway, just shut up.
わわわ全部
Wa-wa-wa, it's obvious
無駄そうに決まってんじゃん
it's all useless.
肺酸圧が強すぎ
My pulmonary pressure is too high,
ベイビベイクアクセル
baby, bake the accelerator.
噛み合わないで
Can you laugh
笑えるくらい？
when things don't fit?
それならこのまま行くしかないか
In that case, there's no choice but to keep going like this.
百歩譲ってそれのがいいか
Conceding a hundred steps, is that better?
大丈夫
It's alright.
無理無理
No way, no way.
納めて
Put it away.
僕しか
Things only I
会えないこと
can meet.
仲良くしてるの
We're getting along well.
どうせなら
If that's the case,
噛ましてみてちゃいますか
why not try to bite into it?
達成妄言
Achieving absurd claims
爆音気分刻んでこう
Let's carve out this loud mood
まだ一途Shine
Still faithfully shine
見せつけてても誰かじゃない
Even if I show off, it's not someone else
僕が良いんだよ
It's good that it's me
OK
私を叶える番だろ
It's my turn to make it happen, right?
ワンゼロ突破
Breaking through one zero
溢れ出すねっぱ
Overflowing passion
擦り倒したい楽でしょうみたい
I want to rub it down, it'll be easy
夢がかなっても止まらねぇ
Even if my dreams come true, I won't stop
ため息かせい
No sighs
No No No No No No Good Bye
ビリビリビリビリ
Biri Biri Biri Biri